I don't like being spoken to in a
我不喜欢被人不尊重地说话。
disrespectful way. Um, but I do feel
嗯，但我确实觉得
that whatever is happening is making you
无论发生了什么，都让你感到
upset or sad and I'd like to talk about
难过或伤心，我想和你谈谈
it. Can we do that?
这件事。我们可以吗？
Now, what I just said was two things.
现在，我刚才说了两件事。
The first one is I don't like being
第一件是我不喜欢被
spoke to in disrespect, which means I
不尊重地说话，这意味着如果你
will end this conversation if you
继续这样，我会结束这次对话。
continue this way. That's called drawing
这叫划定界限。
a boundary. I'm saying don't talk to me
我是在说别这样跟我说话。
this way. That is a boundary. You talk
这就是界限。你这样跟我说话，
to me this way, the conversation's over.
对话就结束了。
But there is an element of kindness
但这里也有一丝善意，
because I'm respecting the fact that
因为我尊重你是人，你因为
you're human and you're upset about
某事而难过，我想和你一起
something and I want to work with you to
努力让你感觉好些。
make you feel better. So even though I'm
所以即使我说这是界限，
saying this is a boundary, I'm saying as
我也在说只要你尊重我的界限，
long as you respect my boundary and
不用那样跟我说话，
don't speak to me in that way, I will
我会帮助你，或者尽力让你感觉好些，
help you or try to help you feel better
或者努力让事情顺利进行。
or try and make this work. Okay? So
好吗？这就是第一点。
that's the first one. So it talks about
它谈到了
respect, respect for the other person
尊重，对他人的尊重。
and respect for yourself. You're asking
以及对你自己的尊重。你在请求
them to respect you and you will respect
他们尊重你，而你也会尊重
them and help resolve the problem or
他们，并帮助解决问题或
situation. Okay? And this is, you know,
情况。明白吗？这，
can be used almost any time and it
几乎可以在任何时候使用，
should be the first line of defense
并且应该是谈论彼此尊重时的第一道防线，
talking about respect for each other,
关于相互尊重，